you know when you're in high school or
middle school or something and you know
you have a friend and and you kind of
like them and you're listening to them
described somebody they like it's this
like kind of sinking feeling you know I
was always very sheltered I never really
dared to really Express exactly how I
felt about someone so for this I just
wrote it kind of this confession into a
song
[Music]
I think the reason it's resonating is I
think it's two-pronged I think maybe
it's a sound that they haven't really
heard before it's kind of you know
infused with like these Bossa Nova and
Jazzy grooves that I think haven't
really been at the Forefront in pop
music for a while I think it's also just
the brutal honesty of the lyrics I think
a lot of people have felt that way
before
[Music]
me and you and awkward
s don't you dare look at me that way
I don't need reminders of how you don't
feel the same I talk a lot but when I'm
with someone I really like I get quiet
and I guess I'm kind of addressing to
this person I'm like don't you notice I
get quiet when it's just the two of us
and it's just me and you in awkward
silence and they're like looking at you
kind of in a loving way but not really
then you're like don't look at me that
way it's just like a reminder that you
actually can't have them
oh the burning pain listening to you
harp on bout some new soulmate She's So
Perfect blah blah blah how I wish you
wake up Wonder
run to me confess your love out
I think this is the funniest verse the
burning pain I kind of almost see it as
this kind of like very like all the
burning pain like almost like this
period drama type of you know of being
upset over someone and yeah she's so
perfect like blah blah blah which I
really enjoy putting lyrics like that
into these like kind of jazzy songs
because it's like it sounds like old
music but then like the blah blah blah
lyric is very very modern I would say
that when I talk to you you bit walks
right through and shoots on the road
through my heart
and I sound like don't you feel it
I wanted the chorus to be this just
straight up like confession of love that
I would never actually dare to say in
person and that's where the craziness
comes from that speculation like wait if
I'm holding back and not telling you
maybe you're holding back and not
telling me
Firebird
[Music]
I grew up listening to a lot of Ella
Fitzgerald and she was kind of like my
singing Idol she is known as the
originator of of scatting in jazz music
of improvisational singing I always had
a dream of kind of bringing it back to
this generation and bring it back to pop
music I'm sure a lot of kids are
listening and like oh my God why is she
singing
for an entire verse but um
fun
what's up
unrequited terrifying Love Is Driving Me
Up
the inside
have to get this off my chest
today I kind of imagine this verse as
like
17 year old me like lying on my bed just
going crazy and staring out into the
night sky hence the blue the blue
definitely had a double meaning it was
both you know literally staring out into
the night sky and also like staring into
like this sadness
[Music]
just thinking
I know I've loved you
from
the storms
in jazz music there's often a tag where
like you know you'll lengthen the outro
lengthen the ending the lyrics will
sometimes change and I've always wanted
to do that with my own music so instead
of confess I loved you from the start
it's just this very clear I know I've
loved you from the start the music
underneath kind of breaks away from this
like upbeat Bossa Nova thing and just
goes straight into like a classical
cello ending which I played I had like a
very specific classical reference that I
wanted for it and I almost wanted it to
sound like a sunset
well scouting is like vocal Freedom you
know ad-libbing in an r b and like pop
music is also kind of scatting it's just
different syllables it's this kind of
freedom and improvisation and singing
that you know we think is reserved for
instrumentalists only but it's also for
singers